asdk12.org 2005-12-10

# Anchorage School District General Information

Information Collected and How it is Used | Personal Information |  How Personal Information is Used |  Rules for Sending Comments | Security | Cookies | Notification of Changes | Links | Contact Us | Definitions

#### PDF version [ ](http://www.adobe.com/products/acrobat/readstep.html) | Text version

## Information Collected and How it is Used

> If you do nothing during your visit but browse or download information, we collect and store the following information about your visit:
> 
>     * The Internet Protocol Address and domain name used but not the e-mail address 
>     * The type of browser and operating system you used 
>     * The date and time you visited the site 
>     * The web pages or services you accessed at this site 
>     * The web site you visited prior to coming to this site
> 

> 
> This information is automatically collected and is used to improve the content of our web services and to help us understand how people are using our services. These logs are not personally identifiable and we make no attempt to link them to individuals.

back to top

## Personal Information

> We don't collect any personal information unless you voluntarily provide it by sending us e-mail, participating in a survey, or completing an on-line form. You may choose not to contact us by e-mail, participate in a survey or to provide any personal information using an online form. Your choice to not participate in these activities will not impair your ability to browse the organization's web site and read or download any information provided on the site.
> 
> Types of personal information that are requested on this site through online forms include:
> 
>     * Your name 
>     * Your e-mail address 
>     * Your phone number 
>     * Your role in our community (i.e. parent, student, district employee, other, etc.) 
>     * Other information volunteered in response to a survey
> 

back to top

## How Personal Information is used

> ### E-mail
>
>> If you send an e-mail to us, it will be forwarded to those individuals (employees, school board members) necessary to address that e-mail. E-mail is recognized as written communication and is considered public record. If a request for public information is submitted to the district, any information contained in that e-mail, including the address, could be released.
>> 
>> If you choose to provide personal information about yourself in that e-mail, we will use the information only to respond properly to your request or to fulfill the stated purpose of the communication. We will not disclose any personal information you decide to provide us, unless disclosure is required by state law or school board policy (School Board Policy 823.51 "Availability of Records"). We do not share, disclose or sell e-mail addresses to other organizations.
>> 
>> Please also keep in mind that e-mail is not necessarily secure against third party interception. If your communication is very sensitive or includes personal information, you may want to contact us by postal mail or telephone instead.
> 
> ### Forms
>
>> If you use one of our public comment forms your name, contact information, and comments may be subject to public disclosure. They will be considered written communication and could be released subject to the guidelines outlined in  School Board Policy 823.51 "Availability of Records."
>> 
>> Phone numbers and emails collected through these forms are used only by members of the board and school district employees to respond to your comments. We do not share, disclose or sell e-mail addresses or phone numbers to other organizations.
> 
> ### E-mail Lists
>
>> The information we collect when you subscribe to one of our e-mail lists is used solely to administer these lists and is not shared, disclosed or sold to other organizations.

back to top

## Rules for Sending Comments

> The Board shall not hear any complaints against pupils or District employees unless such complaints have been heard by the superintendent through proper channels, including the Citizens Complaint process. Exceptions to this policy include negotiated agreements, which may have overriding appeals language, and civil or legal appeals, which supersede School Board authority. 

back to top

## Security

> The Anchorage School District takes every precaution to protect our user's information. If you are a member of one of our e-mail lists, your subscription information will be stored in a secure database solely for our use in sending the announcements. 

back to top

## Cookies

> Certain features of the Anchorage School District's web site require that your browser accept cookies. If you have chosen to turn off cookies in your browser, you will not have access to these particular features of the ASD web site, but it will not affect your use of the site otherwise. 
> 
> Currently the only pages that use cookies are the new myASD pages. The cookie is created only if you log in to myASD, and it will not affect your use of anything outside of the myASD pages. 
> 
> These pages use what is known as a "session cookie" so that the server can keep track of you while you use the myASD service. When you log out of myASD or quit your browser, the cookie is destroyed and nothing permanent is left on your machine. If you go to a different web site without logging out of myASD or without quitting your browser, the myASD session cookie will still be on your machine, but it will not be readable or usable by any other web site. 
> 
> _This section was updated August 16, 2001_

back to top

## Notification of Changes

> Any changes to this privacy statement will be posted on our homepage.

back to top

## Links

> This web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of other sites and when you link to these other sites the Anchorage School District's privacy statement no longer applies. We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information.

back to top

## Contact Us

> You may contact the Anchorage School District as follows:
>
>> > Anchorage School District  
>  4600 DeBarr Road  
>  PO Box 196614  
>  Anchorage, AK 99519-6614  
>  Telephone: 907-742-4000
> 
> Contact information for members of Anchorage School Board  can be found on our web site.
> 
> The Anchorage School District standard for e-mail addresses is lastname_firstname@asdk12.org. If you need assistance, please contact the Webmaster at [webmaster@asdk12.org](mailto:webmaster@asdk12.org).
>
>> **_Please note:_** Anchorage School District e-mail is a tool for business and school communication.  Public users are responsible for using this resource in an efficient, effective, ethical and lawful manner. All e-mails sent to the Anchorage School District should follow the same code of conduct expected in any other form of written communication or face-to-face business and school communication.  Please limit your e-mail to official school business.  Failure to follow these guidelines may result in the loss of access to Anchorage School District e-mail accounts. 
> 
> To offer comments about the web site or about the information presented in this privacy statement:
>
>> > Webmaster  
>  Anchorage School District  
>  4600 DeBarr Road  
>  PO Box 196614  
>  Anchorage, AK 99519-6614  
>  Telephone: 907-742-4193  
>  Fax: 907-742-4175  
> 
> _This section was updated February 14, 2003._

back to top

## Definitions

> **Cookies** are a small text file that a web site can place on your computer's hard drive in order, for example, to collect information about your activities on the site. The cookie transmits this information back to the web site's computer, which generally speaking, is the only computer that can read it. If you want to know when a cookie is being sent or prevent it from happening, you can set your browser to warn you when a web site attempts to place a cookie on your computer.
> 
> **Domain Name** identifies one or more IP addresses. For example: aol.com or gci.net
> 
> **Internet Protocol (IP) Address** is a numerical identifier assigned either to your Internet service provider or directly to your computer. It is used to direct Internet traffic to you.
> 
> **Personal information** is information about a natural person that is readily identifiable to that specific individual. Personal information includes such things as an individual's name, address, and phone number. A domain name or Internet Protocol address is not considered personal information.

back to top

_This privacy statement was:  
  Implemented March 23, 2001  
  "Cookies" section updated August 16, 2001  
  "Contact Us" section updated February 14, 2003_

* * *

[Privacy Policy](http://www.asdk12.org/privacy.asp) | Copyright © 2000-2005  
| [](http://www.asdk12.org/) | Anchorage School District   
4600 DeBarr Road   
PO Box 196614   
Anchorage, Alaska 99519-6614  
---|---|---
